

NIYAS N

E-LEARNING DEVELOPER/INSTRUCTIONAL DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

An eLearning Developer and an Instructional Designer who thrives off of adversity and performs proficiently and collaboratively in fast-paced environments. Creative, outside-the-box thinker, whose narrative-driven learning experiences have positively impacted thousands of team members of various global companies. Motivated self-starter with a high ability to translate and simplify complex digital information for a variety of learners.

CONTACT

Address:

#302, B-3, Aswani Aaeesha, Doddanamgala, Electronic City Phase – 2, Bengaluru, Karnataka - 560100

Phone:

+91 97467 00254 +91 93530 01513

Email:

niyasbinnazeer@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth : 20/07/1996

Age : 28
Nationality : Indian
Marital Status : Single

EXPERIENCE

Senior Analyst

2023 - Present

KPMG GLOBAL SERVICES PVT. LTD.

- → Developing e-Learning courses using authoring tools like Articulate Storyline 360, Evolve, Articulate Rise, etc.
- → Analyze, estimate and develop a complete project as an individual player.
- → Developing storyboards and scripts to guide content production.
- → Creating engaging and interactive course materials, including multimedia elements such as videos animations and interactive simulations.
- → Developing mockups/screens/frames/assets as per design brief, guidelines, and prototype.
- → Communicate with the client, Onshore stakeholders and internal stakeholders on visual design aspects.

Senior Visual Designer

2021 - 2023

TESSERACT LEARNING PVT. LTD.

- → Developing e-Learning courses using authoring tools like Articulate Storyline 360, Domin Know Flow, Articulate Rise, etc.
- → Developing VR Learning Courses using Gmetri, A-Frame, etc.
- → Analyze, estimate and coordinate a project with the given team.
- → Developing mockups/screens/frames/assets as per design brief, guidelines, and prototype.
- → Communicate with internal stakeholders on visual design aspects.

Visual Designer

EI DESIGN PVT. LTD.

2019 - 2021

- → Developed e-Learning courses using authoring tools like Articulate Storyline 360, Articulate Rise, Adobe Captivate, etc.
- → Developed videos using Adobe After Effects, Adobe Premiere Pro, and Flash as per the requirements.
- → Analyze, estimate and coordinate a project with the given team.
- → Developed mockups/screens/frames/assets as per design brief, guidelines, and prototype.
- → Communicate with internal stakeholders on visual design aspects.

Graphic Designer Trainee

2018 - 2019

APTARA LEARNING PVT. LTD.

- → Developed e-Learning courses using authoring tools like Articulate Storyline 3, Adobe Captivate, etc.
- → Supported Motion Graphic Designer in a few projects.
- → Created UI and Mockups for a few HTML and Storyline courses.
- → Quality check for newly developed courses.

EDUCATION

Annamalai University

B.SC VISUAL COMMUNICATION

2019 - 2022

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

English
Malayalam
Tamil
Hindi
Arabic

REFERENCE

MANOJ KUMAR ALLADA

Senior Analyst KPMG Global Services Pvt. Ltd. Phone: +91 99081 49196 Email: manojkumarallada@gmail.com

SRINIVASAN K

Senior Analyst
KPMG Global Services Pvt. Ltd.
Phone: +91 80568 96182
Email: srinisri12@gmail.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Articulate Storyline 360

Captivate

Illustrator

Premiere Pro

Articulate Rise 360

Articulate Rise 360

After Effects

MS Office

Other Tools

GMetri, A-Frame, Adapt Learning, Adobe Indesign, Sony Vegas Pro, Audacity, Adobe Audition, Adobe Flash/Animation, eXact Packager, Vyond

Programming Languages

HTML5, CSS, C++, Java, Javascript

PORTFOLIO

E-Learning https://niyas-portfolio.webflow.io/

Graphic Design https://www.behance.net/gallery/83445797/My-Portfolio

STRENGTHS



Optimistic and time management skills



Ability to work in a team



Hard working, dedicated and quick learner



Leadership quality

HOBBIES



Music



Swimming



Reading



Photography

